gunbuyer.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy- Guns For Sale- Gunbuyer - Gunbuyer

Effective Date: Updated May 25, 2018

At GunBuyer, your privacy is our priority. We are committed to protecting your privacy at all times, in all situations. Gunbuyer.com wants you to be aware of how we collect, use or share information. Our privacy policy indicates how we collection information, what information we store, how long we store it and how it is used. Should you have any questions regarding this policy please feel free to reach out to us at [privacy@gunbuyer.com](mailto:privacy@gunbuyer.com).

**Personal Information**

When you become a GunBuyer.com customer or use our website to submit inquiries, we may ask you to fill out a form that requests your name, address, e-mail address, credit card information, etc. This information is used solely to process orders, provide requested service, and to provide promotional materials from Gunbuyer unless your prior consent is given. Personal information includes anything that identifies you as an individual, including:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Telephone number
  * Postal address
  * Billing address
  * Credit or debit card number
  * Additional information shared by you via email correspondence, etc**

**This may include optional account information you provide such as: DOB, Gender, etc. 

**How We Collect Personal Information**

We collect personal information in a variety of ways including: registering for an account on our website, submitting an order, signing up for our email newsletter, submitting a form on our website, requesting service via email, social media platforms, joint marketing partners, public databases and other third parties.

*Please do not send sensitive information via email including credit card/debit card numbers, social security information, etc.

**How We Use Personal Information We Collect**

We, and our partners, use personal information for legitimate business purposes such as:

  * To provide the services requested by you: respond to inquiries, complete transactions, provide you related customer service, and any other business procedures necessary to fulfill your requests
  * To send information about our business including changes in policy, marketing and sales emails for items you may have interest in
  * To solicit feedback on our service and products
  * To periodically run giveaways and/or sweepstakes
  * To enhance your personal user experience with Gunbuyer.com
  * To protect against fraudulent activity and potential security breaches
  * To analyze data for improved site performance and services for our customers
  * To gauge interest in our marketing campaigns and make needed adjustments

**Who We Share Your Personal Information With**

When submitting your personal information on our site, our social media platforms or any other avenue where information is collected for Gunbuyer.com that information may be disclosed to third party service providers who provide services such as payment processing, order fulfillment, web hosting, data analysis, email marketing, customer service and related services that allow us to operate and provide requested services and information we think may be of interest to you.

Your personal information may also be disclosed should we have a legal obligation or to protect ourselves and/or the customer from unlawful activity. This includes enforcement of terms, complying with law enforcement requests, complying with judicial proceedings, court order and any other situation where protection of all party’s rights & safety may permit us to do so.

**Non-Identifying Information**

When you visit Gunbuyer.com we collect information that does not identify you as an individual but helps us to provide high quality service to all. This includes the use of cookies which collects non-identifiable information about website traffic. This information includes:

  * IP address (this does not identify your specific location merely a city or region)
  * Browser and device information
  * Demographic information
  * Website activity (pages visited, time spent on site, site search keywords, etc)
  * Referral information (where you came to our site from)

All of this information is collected for the purpose of conducting site performance evaluations, the quality and relevance of the information displayed, and your overall user experience. If you do not wish to enable cookies, most browsers offer an opt-out to decline the use of cookies. Contact your browser provider for more details.

We analyze this anonymous information using Google Analytics. You have the ability to opt out of this default service by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser.

Visit: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**Links To Other Sites**

This Web site contains links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you may be leaving the GunBuyer.com site and entering another website. These sites may independently collect or request information about you and we encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their privacy policy may differ from ours.

**Social Media Platforms**

Please note, when visiting any of our social media pages we are not responsible for the information that these platforms collect on an independent basis. Please read the terms and conditions of use on these channels.

**How We Protect & Store Your Personal Information **

Protecting our customers' personal information is extremely important to GunBuyer. In order to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of customer information, we have put in place the appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure any information we collect online. In addition, to protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting order access or making data corrections. This may include requests for identification in cases of suspected fraud. This information is not shared and used solely for the purpose of confirming identity to protect against credit card theft.

Our 128 bit secure sockets layer (SSL) software provided by Veri-Sign is the industry standard and is among the best software available today for eCommerce transactions. This software, SSL, encrypts all your personal information including your name, address, credit card numbers and any other information you provide through SSL.

Our external servers and internal computer systems that contain our databases are firewall protected and continually updated daily to prevent intrusions from outsiders.

**How Long We Store Your Personal Information**

We retain your personal information for as long as is pertinent and we have a business relationship. Information provided by you is kept on our servers until requested otherwise, this includes: customer accounts, email addresses, order information, and any other correspondence showing record of services requested and offered. Email lists are purged quarterly to remove inactive users that no longer respond to our marketing campaigns.

Per federal law, we are required to retain all firearm transfer information for any firearm order placed through our site. This includes, name, address, contact information, transferring FFL information, firearm purchased, serial number of firearm, and any other information that may be requested by law enforcement agencies.

**Opt-Out**

From time to time we may send out email messages alerting you that products are available, to remind you about providing feedback or for promotional offers. In addition, you will receive communication from us 1) if you contact us for a particular reason, 2) to receive your orders, or 3) we need to contact you for administrative purposes such as winning a contest. Administrative e-mails will not contain promotional materials. By submitting a form on our site, submitting an order or registering for an account, you agree to receive future emails and promotions from Gunbuyer.com.

Should you no longer wish to receive our email communications moving forward you may opt-out by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each of our marketing emails. You may also email us at [sales@gunbuyer.com](mailto:sales@gunbuyer.com) to request removal from our email list.

Please be advised that we may still send emails with regard to orders you place, administrative notices and other customer service related messages that are for the purpose of fulfilling your requests.

**Personal Information Access**

Under the new GDPR guidelines, members of the EU and Switzerland have the right to request their stored personal information to review, update, suppress or delete. For these purposes you may email [privacy@gunbuyer.com](mailto:privacy@gunbuyer.com).

**Use of Website by Minors**

Due to the nature of our products, anyone under the age of 18 is not permitted to utilize our services. By visiting our site or placing an order you are confirming that you are of legal age to do so. Gunbuyer.com is not responsible for the use of our site by those that are under the age of 18.   

**What Are Cookies?**

Cookies are data stored on the end-user's hard drive with information that relates directly to the end-user's visit to our web site. Any information placed in the cookie is accessible only to GunBuyer.com and will not be sold or shared with anyone else. We use a cookie to store a unique session identifier, which allows us to maintain shopping cart and web site selections from one-page request to the next and maintain session information from one visit to the next. By setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in more than once, thereby saving time while visiting our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still browse our site. However, the user experience will be greatly curtailed. In addition, the user will be unable to log in or make a purchase. Cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance users' experience and display products that relate directly to individual user preferences.

**Updates**

Updates may be made to this privacy policy at any time. By using our website and services you are agreeing to the policies that govern this website, including this privacy policy.   

**Your Feedback is Always Welcome**

Should you have any questions regarding the collection, processing or storage of your personal information please do not hesitate to contact us below:

Gunbuyer.com

1050 South Nova Rd.

Ormond Beach, FL 32174

Ph: 855-318-4867

Fax: 855-772-5673

privacy@gunbuyer.com
